# Nehal Bhandari

System Engineer | 9284671169 | nehalvbhandari@gmail.com | Whitefield, Bangalore, 560066

### **Summary**

Working as Quality Assurance in TCS with over 2 years of experience. Seeking for an opportunity to pursue my interest as a JS full-stack web application developer. Have over a year of experience in building responsive, optimized, secure and structured web application using React. Have knowledge of present-day frameworks and technologies. Looking to be a part of a progressive organization that gives a scope to enhance my knowledge and utilize my skills towards the growth of the company.

#### **Technical Skills**

- Programming Languages: C, C++, Java, JavaScript.
- Selenium tool for testing with Java.
- Web Development: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Sass, Tailwind CSS, JQuery, ReactJS, NextJS, NodeJS, Redux, ExpressJS, Rest API.
- Data Systems: Firebase, SQL, MongoDB
- Android Application Development, Android Studios
- MERN Stack for Web development
- Tools: Git, npm, Firebase, Heroku, Postman

## **Work Experience**

**TCS, Bangalore** – *Quality Assurance, System Engineer* November 2020 – Present

- Worked as IT in a Data Warehouse Project.
- Integral part of the team for timely delivery of User Stories.
- Analysis of User Stories to bring out the best possible solutions and work around.
- Execution of Test cases with detailed Report generation.
- Building Automation testcase and running using GTAF (Framework). Java & IntellJ
- Tools: qTest for Execution and Jira to track User Story progress.
- Worked on Release Test Plan, Scope Documents and Release Test Report.
- · Worked on Presentation of WSR with Clients.
- · Awards Received: Special Initiative.

#### TCS, Bangalore – Assistant System Engineer

August 2019 – October 2020

- Part of a Pilot project for TCS with European Client.
- Integral part of the team to help with Integration of the tool in a desired way
- Execution of Test cases with detailed Report generation.
- Defect Analysis with the Team and ALM tool.
- Worked on creating the best possible detection algorithm for RCA categories along with Regular Expressions.
- Worked on Presentations and Application Demos for Client.
- Worked with team to assure Defect-Free working of the application.
- Received Awards: Applause for Team, On The Spot Award.

## **Internships**

Dec - Jan 2018

Intern at Helix Tech Pvt. Ltd. Goa | Software Development with technologies Java, Android Development and Web Services.

July 2018

Dot Net Application Development Workshop.

January 2018

Android Development & PHP Programming Workshop.

#### **Education**

Padre Conceicao College of Engineering, Goa - Bachelors of Engineering in Computer

June 2015 - May 2019

Completed degree course and achieved First Class in Computer Engineering from Goa University.

St. Xavier.s HSS, Goa - Science

June 2013 - May 2015

Secured First Class in examination conducted by Goa Board of Secondary and Higher Secondary education.

People's high School, Goa

June 2012 - May 2013

Secured 85.1% percentage in examination conducted by Goa Board of Secondary and Higher Secondary education.

#### **Achievements**

- Selected as a part of Digital Cadre in TCS (Wings 1) that focuses on latest upcoming technologies.
- Cleared ISTQB Certification.
- Completed Udemy Certification in MERN, NextJS, Redux, Web Dev Bootcamp.
- First Place in Hackathon 2018 held during the annual inter collegiate tech event organized by Helix Tech Pvt. Ltd. Goa.

## **Projects**

- MERN Stack Stock Trade Web Application using Data Visualization and Rest API.
- NextJS and ExpressJS Web Application that allows you to view the latest Movies and TV Shows that are currently airing, along with its Box Office details.
- OAuth Login Application using PassportJS, with the ability to create accounts by logging in through Facebook, Google, Twitter, Github or just with simple email and password.
- Portfolio with all my Projects Repositories: nehalbhandari-portfolio.herokuapp.com